Yu Zhang, Ph.D.

Personal Information Date of birth: April 26, 1990 Phone: +8615801382736 Email: zhangyulb@gmail.com

Personal website: https://zhangyulb.github.io

Work Experience

SenseTime Research, Beijing

Senior Researcher, July 2018 - Present

- ♦ 3D video synthesis via deep learning and stereo geometry
- ♦ Gaze understanding and synthesis with GANs

Robot and Automonous Driving Lab, Baidu Research, Beijing

Research Intern, March 2018 - July 2018

- ♦ Semantic understanding of highway road scenes for automonous driving
- ♦ Point cloud rendering and understanding for high-fidelity data synthesis

EDUCATION

Beihang University, Beijing

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science, Sept. 2012 - July 2018, Supervisor: Prof. Qinping Zhao

- ♦ Various optimization frameworks for weakly supervised video object segmentation
- ♦ Instance-level video segmentation with end-to-end deep learning
- ♦ And-or graph representation and inference for video surveillance
- ♦ Visual saliency; 3D scene understanding; Image co-analysis

B.Eng., Computer Science and Engineering, Sept. 2008 - July 2012, GPA - 3.81/4.0

SHORT BIOGRAPHY

Currently I work as a senior researcher at SenseTime. During my career, I am broadly interested in visual understanding and processing problems with principled learning/optimization frameworks. At SenseTime, I am in particular interested in combining 3D geometry and vision/learning techniques to make medias captured by daily devices easier to be understood, manipulated, and created.

I received my Ph.D. degree from Beihang University in 2018, under the supervision of Prof. Qinping Zhao and Prof. Bin Zhou. I also work closely with the CVTEAM led by Prof. Jia Li. In my Ph.D. years, I spent most efforts on developing learning and optimization frameworks for segmenting video objects in weakly supervised manner.

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

* denotes the work that I supervised or extensively engaged in.

Feixiang Lu, Bin Zhou, **Yu Zhang***, Qinping Zhao. Realtime 3D Scene Reconstruction with Dynamically Moving Object using a Single Depth Camera. *Computer Graphics International (CGI)*, 2018. (**Best Paper Award**)

Feixiang Lu, Bin Zhou, Feng Lu, **Yu Zhang***, Xiaowu Chen, Qinping Zhao. Reconstructing Nonrigid Object with Large Movement using a Single Depth Camera. *Computer Aided Geometric Design* (CAGD), 2018

Yu Zhang, Xiaowu Chen, Jia Li, Wei Teng, Haokun Song. Exploring Weakly Labeled Images for Video Object Segmentation with Submodular Proposal Selection. *IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP)*, 2018.

Changqun Xia, Jia Li, Xiaowu Chen, Anlin Zheng, Yu Zhang. What is and What is not a Salient Object? Learning Salient Object Detector by Ensembling Linear Exemplar Regressors. *IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2017. (Spotlight, 8% acceptance)

Yu Zhang, Xiaowu Chen, Jia Li, Chen Wang, Changqun Xia. Semantic Object Segmentation in Tagged Videos via Detection. *IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI)*, 2017.

Yafei Song, Xiaowu Chen, Xiaogang Wang, **Yu Zhang**, Jia Li. 6-DOF Image Localization from Massive Geo-tagged Reference Images. *IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (TMM)*, 2016.

Yu Zhang, Wei Teng, Xiaowu Chen, Jia Li, Zhiqiang He. Local Shape Transfer for Image Cosegmentation. British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC), 2016. (Oral, 10% acceptance)

Yu Zhang, Xiaowu Chen, Liang Lin, Changqun Xia, High-Level Representation Sketch for Video Event Retrieval. SCIENCE CHINA Information Sciences, 2016.

Yafei Song, Xiaowu Chen, Xiaogang Wang, **Yu Zhang**, Jia Li. Fast Estimation of Relative Poses for 6-DOF Image Localization. *IEEE International Conference on Multimedia Big Data (BigMM)*, 2015. (Best Paper Award)

Han Zhang, Xiaowu Chen, **Yu Zhang***, Jia Li, Qing Li, Xiaogang Wang. Cuboids Detection in RGB-D Images via Maximum Weighted Clique. *International Conference on Multimedia & Expo (ICME)*, 2015.

Yu Zhang, Xiaowu Chen, Jia Li, Chen Wang, Changqun Xia. Semantic Object Segmentation via Detection in Weakly Labeled Video. *International Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2015. (Oral, 3.3% acceptance)

Qing Li, Xiaowu Chen, Yafei Song, **Yu Zhang***. Geodesic Propagation for Semantic Labeling. *IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP)*, 2014.

Kai Jiang, Xiaowu Chen, **Yu Zhang***, Qinping Zhao. Video Event Representation and Inference on And-Or Graph. Computer Animation and Virtual Worlds, 2012.

Aewards & Certificates

- Reviewer for TIP, TMM, ACCV
- The Academic Excellence Foundation of BUAA for PhD Students, Beihang University, 2017
- The National Graduate Scholarship, 2015
- The Graduate Innovation Award, School of Computer Science, Beihang University, 2014
- The Changzhao Qian & Xingyuan Shen Scholarship (1st Prize), Beihang University, 2011
- The Excellent Student Award, Beihang University, 2010 2011
- The Undergraduate Mathematical Contest (1st Prize, Rank 1st), Beihang University, 2009
- The National Undergraduate Mathematical Contest (Second Prize in Beijing Region), 2009

Professional Skills

- Specialize in machine learning for computer vision, and graph/numerical optimization
- Familiar with Linux/Windows, Python/Matlab/C++, OpenCV/Qt
- Familiar with deep learning libraries Tensorflow/Pytorch/MXNet/Caffe
- Good at scentific writing & presentation
- Fluent professional English

Interests

- Chinese calligraphy level 4
- Chinese electronic organ level 6